<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Network Analysis and NLP 2022 on Networks and NLP 2022</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/</link><description>Recent content in Network Analysis and NLP 2022 on Networks and NLP 2022</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basics Network Analysis</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/01_networks/1_networks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/01_networks/1_networks/</guid><description> Use the tabs to access content. Theory part is general, R &amp;amp; Python application part language specific.
This session introduces unsupervised machine learning (UML)
Recommended Datacamp exercises: Introduction to network Analysis in Python Introduction to network Analysis in R Theory: Network Analysis R Application - Network Analysis Python Application - Network Analysis Video Slides Use arrows keys on keyboard to navigate. Alternatively fullscreen slides available here Follow along HTML Notebook Colab Notebook Video 1: Intro &amp; Ecosystem Video 2: Network Measures/h2> Video 3: Mini-Case/h2> Follow along Colab Notebook Video 1: Intro &amp; Ecosystem Video 2: Network Measures Video 3: Mini-Case</description></item><item><title>Exercise 1 - Network Analysis</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/00_exercises/exercise1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/00_exercises/exercise1/</guid><description>Introduction In th first Part 2, you will replicate a well known network analysis, with different data and some twists. Data: The data is to be found at: https://github.com/SDS-AAU/SDS-master/tree/master/00_data/network_krackhard (Hint: You neet to download the raw data) Data: What do I get? Background Let the fun begin. You will analyze network datacollected from the managers of a high-tec company. This dataset, originating from the paper below, is widely used in research on organizational networks.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/info/01_infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/info/01_infrastructure/</guid><description>Material Datacamp: Get access to all the Datacamp premium content for free to facilitate your data science journey. Github Provides internet hosting for software development and version control using Git. It offers the distributed version control and source code management (SCM) functionality of Git, plus its own features. It is also commonly used to host open-source projects, including data science projects. If you do not have it already, you are advice to create an account to manage and showcase your work during this semester.</description></item><item><title>Natural Language Processing - Theory</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/02_nlp/0_nlp_theory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/02_nlp/0_nlp_theory/</guid><description>In this part you&amp;rsquo;ll get a 100% code-free intro to (statistical) Natural Language Processing
Recommended Datacamp exercises: Python Intro to NLP Python - also good Feature Engineering for NLP in Python R Introduction to Natural Language Processing in R NLP intro - level of analysis Text representation From BoW to Topic Modeling and Embeddings (optional) History of NLP in Industry - Yoav Goldberg</description></item><item><title>Application: String Manipulation</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/02_nlp/1_nlp_string/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/02_nlp/1_nlp_string/</guid><description> Use the tabs to access content. Theory part is general, R &amp;amp; Python application part language specific.
R Application - String Manipulation Python Application - String Manipulation Follow along HTML Notebook Video Follow along Colab Notebook Video 1 Video 2</description></item><item><title>Assignment 2 - NLP</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/00_exercises/exercise2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/00_exercises/exercise2/</guid><description>Introduction: Building a Hate Speech Classifier This assignment is less structured than previous individual assignments.
You are given a collection of approximately 25k tweets that have been manually (human) annotated. class denotes: 0 - hate speech, 1 - offensive language, 2 - neither
https://github.com/SDS-AAU/SDS-master/raw/master/M2/data/twitter_hate.zip
1. Preprocessing and vectorizaion. Justify your choices and explain possible alternatives (e.g. removing stopwords, identifying bi/tri-grams, removing verbs or use of stemming, lemmatization etc.)
Create a bag-of-words representation, apply TF-IDF and dimensionality reduction (LSA-topic modelling alternatively simply PCA or SVD) to transform your corpus into a feature matrix.</description></item><item><title>Intermediate Network Analysis</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/01_networks/2_networks_intermediate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/01_networks/2_networks_intermediate/</guid><description> Use the tabs to access content. Theory part is general, R &amp;amp; Python application part language specific.
This session introduces to slightly more advanced concepts in network analysis
R Application - Intermediate Network Analysis Python Application - Intermediate Network Analysis Follow along HTML Notebook Notebook Colab Notebook Video 1 Follow along Colab Notebook Video 1: Intro Video 2: Case</description></item><item><title>Lecturers</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/info/02_lecturers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/info/02_lecturers/</guid><description>The team of lecturers.</description></item><item><title>Application: Working with long text</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/02_nlp/2_nlp_longtext/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/02_nlp/2_nlp_longtext/</guid><description>Working with long text and extracting text elements Use the tabs to access content. Theory part is general, R &amp;amp; Python application part language specific.
R Application - Working with long text Python Application - Working with long text Follow along HTML Notebook Video Follow along Colab Notebook can be watched at 1.5x 😉 Link to News-scraping tutorial in the notebook.</description></item><item><title>Bonus - Network Visualization</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/01_networks/4_network_viz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/01_networks/4_network_viz/</guid><description>This session introduces to multimodel natwork analysis concepts
R Application - Ventwork Visualization Follow along HTML Notebook Notebook Colab Notebook Video 1: Node and Edge Visualization Video 2: Graph Layouts</description></item><item><title>Network 2-Mode</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/01_networks/3_networks_2mode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/01_networks/3_networks_2mode/</guid><description> Use the tabs to access content. Theory part is general, R &amp;amp; Python application part language specific.
This session introduces to multimodel natwork analysis concepts
R Application -2-mode Network Analysis Python Application - -2-mode Network Analysis Follow along HTML Notebook Notebook Colab Notebook Video 1: Intro Video 2: Application Follow along Colab Notebook 1/a> Colab Notebook 2 Video 1: Intro Video 2: Case</description></item><item><title>Workshop 1 - Advanced Applications with NLP and Networks</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/03_workshops/01_workshop1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/03_workshops/01_workshop1/</guid><description>In this workshop we will explore some advanced applications that can be approached with NLP tooling and in combination with what you already know. That includes e.g. semantic networks, semantic search, recommender systems.
To follow the case, please get an account at https://www.kaggle.com/
We will be working with developing a Job Recommendation System based on different vectorisation and semantic search techniques.
Follow the day one notebook here: link</description></item><item><title>Application: Vectorization and Topic Modelling</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/02_nlp/3_nlp_topic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/02_nlp/3_nlp_topic/</guid><description> Use the tabs to access content. Theory part is general, R &amp;amp; Python application part language specific.
R Application Python Application Follow along HTML Notebook Follow along Colab Notebook Video Ecosystem Video Tutorial</description></item><item><title>Literature &amp; Resources</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/info/04_litetrature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/info/04_litetrature/</guid><description>While this course does not come with a list of mandatory readings, we will often refer to some central resources in R and python, which for the most part can always be accessed in a free and updated online version. We generally recommend you to use these amazing resources for problem-solving and further self-study on the topic.
Main Literature These pieces of work can be seen as main references for data science using R and Python.</description></item><item><title>Workshop 2 - Science-Patent Matching</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/03_workshops/02_workshop1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/03_workshops/02_workshop1/</guid><description>Today we will be trying to build a science-patent linking pipeline. We will:
generate embedding representations for academic abstracts and patent text we will identify topics within scientific literature using UMAP and HDBSCAN generate search strings based on extracted keywords (cTF-IDF) search patent documents and identify related technologies (Using Annoy) Data for the project Download
Follow the day one notebook here: :::: HERE ::::
Finished notebook (not well commented): :::: HERE ::::</description></item><item><title>Application: Supervised ML and NLP</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/02_nlp/4_nlp_supervised/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/02_nlp/4_nlp_supervised/</guid><description> Use the tabs to access content. Theory part is general, R &amp;amp; Python application part language specific.
R Application Python Application Follow along HTML Notebook Note: Re-Purposed from another course Follow along Colab Notebook Video SLM Video Semantic Search</description></item><item><title>NLP - Final Assignment</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/info/05_final_assignment_nlp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/UNISTRA-DS-2022/info/05_final_assignment_nlp/</guid><description>What to do? Outline a problem relevant within (evolutionary) economics, innovation studies, economic geography or related disciplines. Below some examples:
Science-Technology Linking Literature mapping exercises Prediction of financial indicators (from text) Solve the problem (in part) using NLP methods
Prepare a well commented notebook (R/Python) to present your work.
You can work in groups.
Submit work to Roman (roman@business.aau.dk) and/cc Daniel (dsh@business.aau.dk)
Deadline: 13/3; 23:59 🤓
Please write if you have further questions.</description></item></channel></rss>